<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-01T10:21:23+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Home</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><author><name>Christian B. Henriksen</name></author><entry><title type="html">Pursuing a Career in Cyberspace</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/pursuing-a-career-in-cyber/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pursuing a Career in Cyberspace" /><published>2022-04-29T21:34:30+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-29T21:34:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/pursuing-a-career-in-cyber</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/pursuing-a-career-in-cyber/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Cyberspace.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;this-post-is-in-progress&quot;&gt;THIS POST IS IN PROGRESS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this blog post, I will try to enlighten some of the questions that a new candidate in this industry might stumble upon. I will build my points on my own experience being &lt;strong&gt;fairly new&lt;/strong&gt;, therefore might this not apply to you. However, I’m sure that you can relate to at least, some of the upcoming points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#this-post-is-in-progress&quot;&gt;THIS POST IS IN PROGRESS&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#pencil2-why-even-write-about-this&quot;&gt;:pencil2: Why even write about this?&lt;/a&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#space_invader-my-way-onto-the-cybership&quot;&gt;:space_invader: My way onto the cybership&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#question-endless-opportunities&quot;&gt;:question: Endless opportunities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#running-certification-race&quot;&gt;:running: Certification Race&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#sunglasses-imposter-syndrome&quot;&gt;:sunglasses: Imposter syndrome&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#collision-tips--tricks&quot;&gt;:collision: Tips &amp;amp; tricks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;I hope you enjoy this post. Feel free to reach out to me.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pencil2-why-even-write-about-this&quot;&gt;:pencil2: Why even write about this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, why do I even care about writing this blog post? It’s simple… I could have used some of these points when I was about to pursue a career in this industry. The industry is very complex, and there are tons of ways into this, which can make it hard for new people to join the spaceship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These new candidates might have fancy bachelor’s degree from the University, vocational education, or be 100% autodidact - my point is, that they (to some degree), have the same fundamental way into this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;space_invader-my-way-onto-the-cybership&quot;&gt;:space_invader: My way onto the cybership&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you don’t want to read about my journey into Cyberspace, you can skip this part.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My way into this field has (maybe) been quite different, compared to what others might have done in the past, but nevertheless - I’m here now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let’s start with my education.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I graduated from Aalborg University with a BSc. degree in Information Technology in 2020. The degree was focused a lot on business continuity and evolvement within the IT industry. This gave me a lot of theoretical knowledge about &lt;em&gt;“how it should be done”&lt;/em&gt;, but no practical experience, which might be valuable for a company.  However, as a side hustle, I worked as a Software Developer for a small start-up - where I developed some of the missing lack of knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After i graduated, I was unsure whether to pursue a Masters degree, or go straight for a entry-level position. I knew that I wanted to work with security, and I knew that i had to get some more knowledge within this field.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So i had two options:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go for additional two years to University, to pursue a Masters degree in something “conventional”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Apply for an entry level position within a security company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while surfing the internet for open job listings, and degrees, I stumbled upon a new conscript the Danish Military is offering - Cyberværnepligten (&lt;em&gt;The Cyber Conscript&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly read through the material, and immediately applied to this. Here in Denmark, you usually have to go through 4 months of conscript, but this education had additional 6 months of cyber-education untop - which for me sounded super interesting and fun. At that point, I hadn’t served my conscript yet, and I found this opportunity a great way for me to take a year off, and think about my future - which turned out to be a great decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got accepted to the conscript, The Cyber Conscript, and for the first time had to experience what it was to be in the military - I had to get fit.  :muscle:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After serving 4 months in the Royal Danish Navy as the initial conscript, I moved to the Army to get my intensive cyber education. In the six months I served I got educated in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Networking(CCNA)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Server administration (Win &amp;amp; Linux)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Microsoft Active Directory Services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Powershell Scripting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Backup Solutions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Governance, Risk &amp;amp; Compliance (GRC)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red teaming techniques and tactics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And Incident Response&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is probably something else to add to the list, but this was just what I had in mind.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All these skills were used at the end of the conscript, on a week exercise. In this exercise, we had to act as System administrators for a whole battalion of actors, which exposed us to a lot of different cases. At the end of the exercise, we had to act as Incident responders, as our infrastructure got infected with widespread malware, which we later found out was ransomware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these skills touched upon a lot of different subjects that are widely used within this industry - at least this was a good way for me to get more practical experience and knowledge about the more technical aspects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even before my conscript was over, I applied for an entry-level position, as a First Responder within the Danish Healthcare, at a huge organisation with over 35,000 employees to manage. I got the job based upon my understanding of &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;processes&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;technology&lt;/em&gt;, but primarly my &lt;strong&gt;drive to learn.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I have worked for this organization for 11 months, and really developed some valuable skills, because one thing is to get an understanding of the technical skills, but there are also soft skills to be added to your resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, something simple as just working for a big organization, where everything is tied to processes, guidelines, and policies - was something new for me. Or the experience that I’ve gotten from the military where you had to work in different environments with people with different backgrounds and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based upon these skills I got a new job as a Cyber Security Consultant in a private cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;:stars: Enough about my way into cyberspace - let’s talk about your opportunities.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;question-endless-opportunities&quot;&gt;:question: Endless opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/roadmap.jpg&quot; /&gt;
One of the questions that I hear a lot in this field, is what path to take if you want to work in this industry. It’s a legitimate question, and I had it myself. This industry has so many different areas, and &lt;strong&gt;the important part&lt;/strong&gt; is for you to do you &lt;strong&gt;research&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;test something&lt;/strong&gt; out. Do you think &lt;em&gt;vulnerability management&lt;/em&gt; is interesting? - Spin up a VM with OpenVAS and try it out. What about &lt;em&gt;penetration testing?&lt;/em&gt; It’s easy for you to create an account on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackthebox.com/&quot;&gt;HackTheBox&lt;/a&gt; and try to see if you can get access to some of the boxes. The only limit is you - there is tons of free ressources in cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, you won’t become an expert with these techniques, but you develop some fundamental skills to do further research and explore your interest. That’s usually a valuable skill for the company you want to work for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get overwhelmed by the tons of options, I suggest you do the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write down your passion&lt;/strong&gt;. What type of work can you get lost in? What type of work could you do every day, and not get sick of? What interests you? Do you like solving puzzles and breaking into stuff - &lt;em&gt;Penetration testing&lt;/em&gt; might be something for you. Do you like keeping yourself up to date with the latest breach reports - &lt;em&gt;Threat intelligence&lt;/em&gt; might be something you fancy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write down your strengths &amp;amp; weaknesses&lt;/strong&gt;. What are you good at? Do you want to work with that, or do you want to evolve your skills in what you are not good at? These are questions that you need to address. And it can be very beneficial to work on your strengths, but occasionally it can be healthy to go out of your comfort zone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can enable yourself to go from just going to work because &lt;strong&gt;you have to&lt;/strong&gt;, to going to work because it &lt;strong&gt;interest you&lt;/strong&gt; - then you have found your right place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;running-certification-race&quot;&gt;:running: Certification Race&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sunglasses-imposter-syndrome&quot;&gt;:sunglasses: Imposter syndrome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;collision-tips--tricks&quot;&gt;:collision: Tips &amp;amp; tricks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;</content><author><name>Christian B. Henriksen</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Career" /><category term="Cybersecurity" /><category term="Education" /><category term="Tips &amp; Tricks" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">FDCA - Foreningen for Danske Cyber Alumner</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/foreningen-for-danske-cyber-alumner/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="FDCA - Foreningen for Danske Cyber Alumner" /><published>2022-04-18T21:34:30+02:00</published><updated>2022-04-18T21:34:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/foreningen-for-danske-cyber-alumner</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/foreningen-for-danske-cyber-alumner/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is in Danish, and will eventually be posted in English&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fdca_logo.png&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; width=&quot;500&quot; style=&quot;border-radius:50%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hvad-er-cyberværnepligten&quot;&gt;Hvad er Cyberværnepligten?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Cvpl_logo.png&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberværnepligten er et politisk udspil der skal udklække ~30+ nye digitale sikkerhedstalenter om året - vis formål er at være ambassadører for god IT-sikkerhed i det danske kongerige.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Værnepligtsperioden er samlet 10 måneder, delt op i to sektioner:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 måneders grundlæggende værnepligt, i et af de tre værn (Hæren, Flyvevåbenet eller Søværnet)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 Måneders cyberuddannelse ved Føringstøtteregimentet i Fredericia. Uddannelsen indeholder desuden to ugers praktik og afsluttes med en uges incident response øvelse.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Der er forskellige krav for at kunne blive optaget på denne uddanelse, du skal b.la. kunne sikkerhedsgodkendes til HEMMELIG, og bestå en prøve der kortlægger dine IT-færdigheder.
Det skal dog siges, at man behøver ikke have de vilde tekniske kompetencer, men blot en nysgerrighed for at lære, og en grundforståelse for de komponenter en computer og et netværk består af.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efter du har gennemført denne intensive uddannelse kan man enten vælger at fortsætte i en militærstilling i Forsvaret, eller tage det civile spring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I dag er der flere tidligere cyberværnepligtige, som eksempelvis arbejder som incident respondere, cyberanalytikere og penetration testere i firmaer som Sundhedsdatastyrelsen, Region Midt og F-secure. Nogle har også valg at fortsætte i Forsvaret ved blandt af Føringsstøtteregimentet, Efterretningsregimentet og Koncern IT (KAKI)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lyder Cyberværnepligten som noget for dig?
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://karriere.forsvaret.dk/varnepligt/varnepligten/cybervarnepligt/&quot;&gt;Så kan du læse mere om den her&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hvad-er-fdca&quot;&gt;Hvad er FDCA?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/fdca_logo_long.png&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; style=&quot;margin:0 auto;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;FDCA er en forkortelse for Foreningen for Danske Cyber Alumner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreningens formål er:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bidrage til Danmarks og Rigsfællesskabets modstandsdygtighed overfor Cyber-trusler.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Udvikle medlemmernes viden, færdigheder og kompetencer inden for Cyber- og IT-sikkerhed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karriererådgivning og eksponering for virksomheder.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fastholde og fremme kammeratskab på tværs af hjemsendte Cyberværnepligtshold.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For at fremme ovenstående formål, så hjælper foreningen med at afholde sociale og faglige arrangementer, samt hjælp til finansering af diverse certificeringer, både med formål at fremme ‘soft-skils’, men også tekniske kompetencer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreningen er altså er fællesskab, hvis formål er at hjælpe alumner der er færdige med deres cyberværnepligt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hvorfor-er-fdca-oprettet&quot;&gt;Hvorfor er FDCA oprettet?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Efter vi (bestyrelsen) selv havde færdiggjort vores værnepligt, så savnede vi et centralt holdepunkt hvori man kunne dyrke cyberværnepligtens unikke fællesskab og bygge videre på de egenskaber, som man havde tilegnet sig over de sidste 10 måneder. FDCA blev derfor oprettet både for at dyrke kammeratskabet, men også fordi der blev set et potentiale i at skabe et centralt samlepunkt, hvor der bland andet tilbydes kompetence- og karriereudvikling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;På nuværende tidspunkt består bestyrelsen af 6 ildsjæle der driver foreningen i samarbejde med et bredt udvalg af foreningens medlemmer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hvad-laver-man-i-fdca&quot;&gt;Hvad laver man i FDCA?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foreningen blev oprettet i September 2021, og har siden da afholdt 2 fysiske arrangementer - det ene var en Capture the flag dag, som blev afholdt på Aalborg Universitet i København. Det andet var et Purple-teaming event, med fokus på threathunting i samarbejde med David Clayton(Combitec) og Nichlas Falk(Improsec), på Combitecs faciliteter i Århus. Til dette event blev APT-gruppen “WizardSpider” analyseret, og deres TTP blev simuleret i et lukket miljø. Dette var med til at give inspiration til hvordan man kan gribe sin threat-hunting an - altså medlemmerne fik udvidet deres “hands-on”-erfaring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_1438.jpg&quot; align=&quot;center&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; width=&quot;550&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foreningen har derudover afholdt et online CTF-event, deltaget i OWASP foredrag og haft forskellige sociale sammenkomster. Selvom det sociale aspekt vægtes højt ved samtlige arrangementer, så går foreningens medlemmer altid hjem med viden eller erfaring, som kan bruges direkte i deres arbejde eller uddannelse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hvor-vil-foreningen-hen&quot;&gt;Hvor vil foreningen hen?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vores førnævnte målsætninger viser, at foreningen har nogle ret seriøst ambitioner, og det er dem, som vi skal ud at jage nu. Det kan dog selvfølgelig være svært at definere og måle på hvordan og hvornår vi gør hele Rigsfællesskabet mere sikkert. Vi er af den overbevisning, at hvis vi fortsætter med af hverve en masse alumner og kan tilbyde dem kvalificeret ”state of the art” kompetence- og karriereudvikling, så skal vi helt sikkert nok lykkes. 
Helt specifikt bruger vi nu blandt andet meget energi på at få stablet nogle varige samarbejder op med forskellige virksomheder. Vi mener, at eksterne samarbejdspartnere er essentielle for at accelerere vores vej mod vores overordnet visioner, men også at vi har en masse ekspertise, som vi kan dele ud af. Derudover har vi en masse spændende arrangementer i pipelinen, som vi glæder os meget til at kunne fortælle mere om.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Har du lyst til at følge med i, hvad foreningen laver, så følg os på:&lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/foreningen-for-danske-cyber-alumner&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, eller vores hjemmeside: &lt;a href=&quot;https://fdca.dk&quot;&gt;FDCA.dk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eller smid os en mail på: 
 info@fdca.dk&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christian B. Henriksen</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Cyberværnepligt" /><category term="Cybersecurity" /><category term="Education" /><summary type="html">This post is in Danish, and will eventually be posted in English</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2019-04-18T21:34:30+02:00</published><updated>2019-04-18T21:34:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-ruby highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;&apos;Tom&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints &apos;Hi, Tom&apos; to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Christian B. Henriksen</name></author><category term="blog" /><category term="Jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry></feed>